Buying term insurance for your family's financial protection is as
important as it is confusing.
We have so many options
that it becomes very difficult to select the right term insurance.
Friends,
in today's video, I have selected the top five term
insurance companies and compared them so that
you can make a good and informed
decision. Also, friends,
in this video, I will also explain on what
parameters I selected these companies
and why these five
companies are the best. Hello friends, I
am Ashutosh, your personal finance coach. Let's
start the video. Friends, the five
term insurance companies selected for comparison are
Max Life's
Smart Secure Plus Plan, TI Life's
Sampoorna Raksha Supreme III, Prudential
Life's iProtect Smart, ADFC
Life's Click to Protect Super, and Bajaj
Ace's eTouch Term Plan. Friends, to select these companies,
we not only looked at the
claim settlement ratio but also the
claim amount ratio, their pending claim
amounts, and rejected claims.  and rejected
amount. Apart from this, the size of the company or
its profitability is also an
important parameter for selecting these companies
because if we are
purchasing term insurance, then we are
purchasing it for the next 20, 30, 40 years,
so we would like to purchase term insurance from such a company
whose future prospects are
quite good. Friends, if we
look at this sheet, for the claim to settlement ratio,
we have taken the average of the last five years.
See the last five year average, Max Life's
98.9, TA E's
98.5, III 98.
What is the amount of claim received and
how much amount of claim has been settled by the company out of that amount.
If we look at these companies,
Max Life's
95.2, TA A's
93.6, AA A's
92.1,
HDFC.com's 92.1, Max Life's 1, TA E 1.45,
Prudential
1.61,
HDFC.com's settlement ratio is that  9596
is above 6 and its amount settlement ratio is
above 90, so we consider it a good
company and
we can buy its term plan. Talking about other features, if we talk about
minimum and maximum entry age, then
in all the five plans the
minimum entry age is 18 years and maximum
entry age is 65 years. Talking about the maximum age at
maturity,
it is 85 years in MaxLife Smart Secure Plus plan, which
means that you will not get the option of whole life cover in this.
In TA EA, you will get a
policy of 100 years.
In III Prudential also, you will get a policy of 99 years, which
means you will get whole life cover for
years. We will pay premium every year.
Limited pay means that we will pay the premium
of our entire entitlement in just a few years
and our policy will continue till the
end. Similarly, in single pay,
we pay the premium of the entitlement in a single premium.
Talking about the return of premium option, this
option  Available in all five plans,
many of us
feel that we have paid the premium, but
if we survive the policy term,
our money will be wasted. In such a situation, the company
offers us the option of return of premium,
which is available in all five plans.
For return of premium, we have to pay a small
extra premium. Up
to 30-35 years, we are
charged extra. In case of return of premium,
talk about special exit value or
nowadays it is very popular. No-cost
term insurance, which means that
in a certain period policy, i.e., if our policy is for a long term, then
after a particular age, the
company gives us the option to
surrender our term insurance and
get our premium back. Let's
suppose you took a policy for 85 years and
after 60, you feel that you do
not need further term insurance. In
such a situation, instead of paying further premium, you can
surrender your policy right there and
get your entire premium back. This
option is available in Max Life.  This is not available
with the Smart Secure Plus plan.
It is not available with the Sampoorna Raksha Supreme.
It is also
not
available with the
IIII Protect Smart. If we feel that we have not taken a policy of a sufficient amount, then we can select this option. In Max Life Insurance, we get the option of increasing sum assured. This option is also available in the Sampoorna Raksha Supreme. This option will not be available in the IIII Protect Smart. We get this
feature. Friends,
I have already made detailed videos related to these five plans,
which you can check by going to the i button above
or by going to the description below.
Friends, as important as it is to
select a right term insurance, it is equally important to take a
policy of the right tenor. Taking a policy of the right amount means
that the amount of policy we have
taken is
sufficient for the future financial needs of our family. So,
friends, if you want to purchase
a right term insurance policy according to your financial situation, you want to
purchase a policy of the right amount and the right tenor.  If you want to know
which riders you should or should not take with your policy, then
you can also purchase your policy with us,
where we will recommend the
right product for you according to your current financial situation.
Talking about spouse cover,
nowadays we get the option of
spouse cover or joint life cover in many insurances, in
which we can cover
our wife or husband along with ourselves in the same policy.
Friends, the
option of joint life cover is available in Max Life's Smart
Secure Plus plan.
We will not get this option in TIE.
This option is also not available in IIII Protect Smart.
Many times we are
not able to get cover for our future financial liabilities. In
these,
we get the option of life stage, in
which we can increase
our life cover against our future liabilities,
which mainly
gives us the option to increase it at the time of our marriage or the birth of children.
Friends, in Max Life's Smart Secure
Plus plan, we get  Voluntary top up
option is available in your sum shot but it is an
additional option, we have to purchase it as a rider
with our plan first.
In this we get this option inbuilt in
which in case of marriage we can enhance the cover up to Rs. 50
for first child, Rs. 25 for second child
and in case of home loan up to the amount of home loan.
We also get this option inbuilt in III Prudential iProtect Smart in
which in case of marriage we can increase our basic sum covered up to Rs. 50
lakh, maximum up to Rs. 25 lakh
in case of first child and
up to Rs. 25 lakh in case of second child also.
hdfc0000052 25 lakh We can increase our coverage.
In Bajaj Allians we can increase our basic sum covered up to Rs.
50 lakh in case of marriage, Rs.
25 lakh in case of first child and up to Rs. 25 lakh
in case of second child.  Up to 25 lakh on 25.
Apart from this, in case of home loan,
up to 50 lakh on 25 lakh sum assured and up
to 25 lakh on education loan for children, you
can increase your coverage.
Friends, an accidental death rider is
very popular with our term
assurance. In case of accidental death rider, apart from our
basic sum assured,
we get a separate coverage payout
and in most of the cases, it is double of our basic
sum shot. Friends,
in all the five plans, we have accidental death
rider available in different options.
Talking about accidental permanent disability rider, it is not available in Max Life. There is a
disability rider in TAA, which means that there is a
separate payout in case of disability. It is
not available in III Prudential iProtect Smart.
Friends, accidental death and accidental
total  Apart from the Permanent Disability Rider, there are
other important riders such
as the Critical Illness Rider, Terminal Illness
Rider, and Waiver of Premium Rider. The
meaning of the Critical Illness Rider is that the
company maintains a list of diseases. If a
policyholder is diagnosed with one of these diseases
and has
this rider, he or she receives a sum assured payout.
Sometimes, this
Critical Illness Benefit is
separate from your policy, meaning its
benefit is paid to you separately.
In some cases, the Critical Illness
Payout is accelerated, meaning
your Basic Sum Assured (BSU) is
reduced from whatever amount you have in your policy. The
Critical Illness Rider offered with the Max Life Smart Secure Plus plan
covers 40 illnesses. Its
benefit is accelerated,
but its benefit is separate and
deducted from your sum assured.  It will not be given.
Even in ICICI Potential Life, the
critical illness benefit
is accelerated. You will get a payout by reducing your time limit.
This rider
covers 34 illnesses. In ADAC Life,
this benefit is separate and it covers 19 illnesses.
You do not get a critical illness rider with the Bajaj SK E-Testament plan,
but
you get the critical illness option with its other plan options. The
next benefit is
terminal illness, which is available in all five plans.
Friends, terminal illness
means an illness which results in
death within a few months of detection. So,
if a policy holder dies in such a case, in which the
doctors
declare that the
policy holder will die within a few months, then
in such a case, the policy
benefit, i.e., death benefit, is already
given to the policy holder.
Talking about the claim option, friends,
in all the policies  We get the option of lump sum income plus lump sum and
monthly income. Friends,
whenever such a large benefit is paid out,
every nominee or
your spouse can
invest
and manage that much financially. However, if they
cannot manage it themselves,
they should select the monthly income option. The
total sum shot
is available under the equal monthly income option, and
in some plans, it is
also available under the increasing income option. If you feel that
your nominee cannot manage it themselves,
but you have a large
loan, such as a home loan, then you can select the lump sum
option for that amount and the
monthly income option for the remaining amount.
Friends,
talking about payout options, Max Life
offers the option of equal monthly income for 10 years. TA IA
also has a maximum monthly income of 10 years.  You
get the option of monthly income for 10 years. In III
Prudential Life iProtect Smart,
we get the option of equal monthly income for 10 years. Along with this,
we
also get the option of increasing income in this plan. You get the
option to select the income option.
In Bajaj Allians, we get the option
of monthly payout for up to 60 months i.e. five years.
Friends,
if you have any doubt related to all these plans, then you
can ask by commenting below.
If you want to purchase any of these plans
or want to discover your financial situation, that is,
how much
amount of policy you should take, how much tenure
of policy should you take. We will recommend the
right term insurance to you according to your personal financial condition given below.
Friends, if you liked the video, then
definitely like it and subscribe to this channel
so that you keep getting such informational
videos. If any of your
friends want to purchase term insurance,
then you can also forward this video to them.
Friends, that's all in today's video.
in the next video
thanks